Finding Aid for Carl Edward Buck papers, 1932-1953
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Carl Edward Buck papers 1932-1953
Buck, Carl Edward, 1891-1953.
1 linear foot
8929 Aa 2
Field director of the American Public Health Association, 1931-1948, later professor of public health administration at the University of Michigan, 1948-1953. Files detailing various community health administration studies that he administered; also thesis and miscellaneous public health materials.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection came to the library in 1971 as part of the records of the University of Michigan School of Public Health (donor no. 1756 ).
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Carl Edward Buck was a professor of public health administration in the School of Public Health at the University of Michigan from 1948-1953. There and in his previous work he developed an international reputation for his work with local health agencies. He was best known for a series of public health surveys conducted on the local, city, and state levels in the United States and Canada.
Buck was born in 1891 in Leipzig, Germany where his father, the noted philologist Carl Darling Buck, was a visiting lecturer. Carl Buck was educated at Hotchkiss School (1907) and Dartmouth College (BS, 1914). He received graduate instruction in public health at Harvard and MIT (1914-1915) and completed a doctorate in public health at the University of Michigan (1922).
Buck served on the U.S. Typhus Fever Commission in the Balkans, 1915-1916, and then worked briefly with the American Red Cross, the California State Health Department, and the International Board of Health of the Rockefeller Foundation. Buck joined the Detroit Department of Health in 1922 where he held a variety of positions until 1930. From 1931 to 1948 Buck was field director of the American Public Health Association.
In recognition of his service to the profession, Buck was awarded the Sedgwick Medal by the American Public Health Association in 1953. Carl Buck died November 21, 1953.
The Carl E. Buck Papers, 1932-1953, consist of one foot of material relating principally to various community health administration studies he carried out as field director of the American Association of Public Health and later as professor of public health administration in the School of Public Health at the University of Michigan. There is one folder of biographical material at the beginning of the collection.
The community study material includes some correspondence, research materials, and the final reports of the studies. Also included in the collection is Buck's Ph.D. dissertation, "An Evaluation of Medical School Inspection in Light of Recent Developments," and an incomplete series of news releases from the Detroit Health Department, 1931-1941.
Subjects:
American Public Health Association.; Public health--United States.; University of Michigan--Faculty.; University of Michigan. School of Public Health.
- Professional papers
  - Biographical Material (Box 1)
  - American Public health Association
    - Committee on Administrative Practice 1949, 1951 (Box 1)
    - Evaluation Schedule Study, 1948-1951, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Field Training Conference, 1950 (Box 1)
    - State and Local Health Administration, 1945-1950 (Box 1)
  - Michigan Public Health Recruitment and Training Board, 1950-1952, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Michigan Technical Committee on Public Health Administration, 1950-1951 (Box 1)
  - Public Health Administration Studies (Box 1)
  - Guide to Community Health Study
    - California, 1951 (Box 1)
    - Dearborn (MI) Schools (Box 1)
    - Idaho, 1945 (Box 1)
    - Illinois, 1942 (Box 1)
    - Illinois, 1952 (Box 1)
    - Manitoba, 1950, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Massachusetts, 1947 (Box 1)
    - Michigan, 1948 (Box 1)
    - Michigan, 1953 (Box 1)
    - Montana, 1946 (Box 1)
    - New York City, 1934, 1952 (Box 1)
    - Oakland County (Box 1)
    - Oregon, 1944 (Box 1)
    - Virginia, 1951 (Box 1)
    - Wyoming, 1946 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous
    - "An Evaluation of Medical School Inspection in Light of Recent Developments" (Ph.D. dissertation), 1922 (Box 1)
    - Inter Chamber Health Conservation Contest, Detroit, 1942 (Box 1)
    - Detroit Health Department News Releases
      - 1931 (Box 1)
      - 1935-1937 (Box 1)
      - 1941 (Box 1)